74年来，苏维埃社会主义强权盛行
For 74 years, the might of Soviet socialism was so great
将世界分成东西两半
it split the world along Eastern and Western lines.
而在1991年，它彻底瓦解了
Then, in 1991, it collapsed completely.
先前追随苏联的各个国家也一个接一个的
One by one, the various countries which had supported the Soviet Union
从中分裂出来，宣布独立
began splitting away, declaring their independence.
东斯拉夫共和国议会经由法律程序
The parliament of the Eastern Slav Republic followed suit,
東斯拉夫共和国
从苏联统治中独立，宣告主权自主
declaring the country a sovereign state, independent from Soviet rule.
资本主义迅速发展
Capitalism advanced rapidly.
使财阀集团的影响力掌控了政坛
The conglomerates gained influence in political circles,
最后形成了寡头政权统治
and as a result, the oligarchs came into power.
东斯拉夫共和国国内
In the Eastern Slav Republic,
贫富差距越来越大
the divide between rich and poor became so great
一股新的反抗势力被点燃了
it ignited the fuse of a new rebellion.
街头爆发了呼吁独立的游行运动
The push for independence exploded into the streets.
对立双方是武装起来的自由斗士
Armed freedom fighters pitted themselves against their government,
和由寡头政治家把控的政府
now controlled by the oligarchs.
在这期间，军方日渐得势
The military prospered during this time,
越来越强，装备也更先进
becoming ever stronger and better equipped.
在长老议一位酋长——伊凡·裘丹纳维奇的领导下
Under the guidance of Ivan Judanovich, an Ataman from the Council of Elders,
自由斗士们将基地迁到隐密之处
the freedom fighters moved their base to a hidden location.
一个更方便与政府打游击战的地方
A more suitable place to launch their guerrilla war against the government.
经过多年无情的争斗
After several years of brutal fighting,
斯维特拉娜贝利科娃
it was Svetlana Belikova,
东斯拉夫第一位女性总统
Eastern Slav's first female president,
向自由斗士提出停战协议
who offered a ceasefire to the freedom fighters.
战争的中断时间很短暂
But the break from hostilities was short-lived.
2010年11月，政府发现
In November of 2010, the government discovered
反叛军的土地拥有贵重资源
that the rebels' land contained valuable resources.
军方又继续开展攻势
The military continued their attacks,
他们声称是在和恐怖主义交战
claiming they were fighting terrorism.
在军方猛攻下，基地一个接一个的失守
Losing one base after another to the military's onslaught,
而自由斗士们则更加激进
the freedom fighters escalated their efforts
在策略上变得越来越极端
and became more and more radical in their tactics.
与此同时，一些诡异的流言
It was then that strange rumors
如星火般在民众之间传开
began spreading like wildfire among the people
有怪物加入了战局
that monsters had joined the battle.
2011年2月
In February of 2011,
流言传到了距总统府仅数公里的
the rumors made it to the old city of Holifgrad,
荷利夫葛拉德旧城区
just a few kilometers from the Presidential Palace,
这里是政府的一个战略要地
an important strategic location for the government.
聆听长老之命令
Listen to the words of the elders.
我们终于获得了所需的力量
We have finally gained the power that we need.
带领我们走向胜利的力量
Power that will lead us to victory.
人民，团结起来
Gather, people.
团结起来，一起战斗
Gather and fight.
为独立自由而战
Fight for independence!
撤退！我们遭到猛烈攻击
Retreat! We're getting slaughtered!
又一个叛军
Another rebel!
-不要拒捕 -撤退
-Do not resist arrest. -Retreat!
放下武器
Drop your weapons.
-即刻投降 -政府走狗
-Surrender immediately.  -Government pigs!
再次警告，放弃抵抗
I repeat, do not resist arrest.
放下武器，即刻投降
Drop your weapons. Surrender immediately.
生化危機
詛咒
向目标地点进发
Moving into position.
收到
COPY-
我从空中能够清楚看到你
I've got a clear view of you from the sky.
好极了
Great.
也许你可以帮我找出中情局的分配路线
Maybe you can help me find a clear route to the CIA drop-off.
看来他们在下面这里做了些重大翻修
Looks like they're doing some serious renovations down here.
仔细听我说，里昂
Listen to me carefully, Leon.
你的任务中止
Your mission has been aborted.
美方将撤离这个国家
The U. S. is going to pull out of the country.
什么？我才刚到这里
What? I just got here.
把我从休假中抓来，派我到这个…
After taking me off furlough and sending me to this
阴森的鬼地方之后？
godforsaken place?
搞什么鬼？
What the hell?
华盛顿与本地政府决定分道扬镳
Washington and the government there have decided to go their separate ways.
不只是外交人员 所有人都必需离开
Everyone has to leave, not just embassy staff
所有美国公民听令 撤离这个国家
All American citizens have been ordered to evacuate the country.
我才不管什么政治纷争
I don't give a damn about the politics.
我们已经证实生化武器 被用在这场战争之中
We've got confirmation that B.O.W.s are being used in this war.
如果现在不阻止他们
If we don't stop them now,
世界各地将会发生相同惨剧
the same shit will happen everywhere.
这是你希望见到的吗？
Do you really wanna see that?
这是战争，情况不一样
This is a war and things are different.
缺乏美国政府的支持 没有人能够擅自行动
No one can do anything without backup from the American government.
连你也不行
Not even you.
那么我想我别无选择
Well then, I guess my only option is to
只能暂时先失去美国公民身份
lose my American citizenship for a while.
里昂
Leon!
她可以跟他们说我迷路 没搭上飞机
She can tell them I got lost and missed my flight.
最好快点完成任务
Better hurry up and get this done.
我要吃早餐
I need some breakfast.
稻草人
Scarecrow.
我是锡铁人，你能说话吗？
I'm the Tin Man. Can you talk?
反政府势力与生化武器之间有什么关联？
What's the connection between the anti-government forces and the B.O.W.s?
我猜稻草人的长处
I guess scarecrows aren't known
不是与人沟通
for rousing conversation.
撑着点
Hang in there.
我会救你出去的
I'll get you out of here.
蜂
Bee--
什么？
What?
再说一遍
Say that again.
蜂
Bee
人
keeper.
养蜂人？
Beekeeper?
我在外面看到的蜜蜂
The honeybee I saw outside.
真倒霉，现在我得面对一只胆小的狮子
Great. Now I got a cowardly lion to deal with.
是军队
It's the army.
有人在吗？
Is anyone here?
搜查楼下的房间
Check the room down there.
嘿
Hey--Unh!
别说话
Don't say a word.
那一间呢？
How about that one?
这间没人
This one's clear.
没人
Clear.
这间没人
This one's clear.
继续行动
We're moving on.
撤出
Pull out.
他们走了
They're gone.
我们最好再留久一点
We better stay here a while longer.
他们有可能会回来
They may come back.
你觉得我们的人质
Do you think our hostage
有用吗？
will be of any use?
你知道我们是谁吗？
Do you know who we are?
你是桃乐丝？
Are you Dorothy?
你们中情局的人称我们为恐怖份子
You people in the CIA call us terrorists.
但我们比较喜欢自称为
But we prefer to call ourselves
独立派斗士
pro-independence fighters.
中情局的人在这里做什么？
What is the CIA doing here?
是你要政府这么做的？
Did you put the government up to this?
你们还有其他人吗？
Are there any more of you?
我不是中情局探员
I'm not a CIA agent.
我只是一个休假休到一半
I'm just an American who was screwed out of his vacation,
被丢上飞机，带到这里来的人
dumped on a plane and brought here.
而且还没吃早餐
Without breakfast.
他们在你度假度到一半时找你？
They came for you while you were on vacation?
巴迪
Hey, Buddy.
他一定是中情局高层 他们才会这样做
He's got to be high up in the CIA for them to do that.
你电影看太多
You watch too many movies.
不然你是谁？
Then what are you?
难道一般美国人
Is it common for people in America
度假时会带这个？
to be packing one of these while on vacation?
当然会，我们从开国起就这样干了
Sure. We've been doing it since the country was founded.
哇，美国真是超炫的
Wow, America's the bomb, yo!
随你怎么讲
Whatever.
就算你不是中情局的人
But even if you're not CIA,
毫无疑问，你肯定有独到之处
there is no doubt you must be pretty special
美国才会派你过来
for America to send you here.
总归你能对抗那玩意
You were able to take on that thing, after all.
如果你再不停止乱搞那玩意
If you don't stop messing around with that thing,
你会把我们全都害死
you're gonna get us all killed.
毫无疑问，你是我们的敌人
There is no doubt about the fact that you are our enemy.
一场反恐怖份子扫荡行动执行中
An anti-terrorist sweep is now in operation.
民众请尽量…
Civilians should avoid
避免外出
going outside as much as possible.
如果见到可疑人物
If you see any suspicious people
或可疑行为
or behavior,
请立刻通报有关当局
report it to the authorities immediately.
情况汇报
Status.
有些人逃到地下
Some escaped underground.
但是逮捕他们是迟早的事
But it's only a matter of time before they are rounded up.
说详细一点
Tell me in more detail.
到底是什么时候？
When, exactly?
这个…
Well...
是这样子的
You see--
同样的错误你还要犯多少次？
How many times are you going to make the same mistake?
我们早在五年前就该成为联合国一员
We should have become a member of the United Nations five years ago.
至今成为欧盟国际社会中
And by now be a respected member
备受尊敬的成员
of the international community in our role as an EU nation.
但是在这件事成真之前
But before that could happen,
另一群人从下水道爬出来
another group came crawling out of the sewers,
大喊分离宣言
screaming their declarations of separatism.
而这种事之所以会发生的主要原因
And the main cause of this
就是因为你纵容恐怖份子为所欲为
is because you allowed the terrorists to do as they please.
如果我们不快点行动
If we don't act soon,
我们将永远失去真正独立的机会
we will lose our chance for true independence forever.
我们不能让这种事发生
And we cannot allow that to happen
要不计一切代价
at any cost.
总统阁下
Madam President.
您的访客到了
Your visitor has arrived.
带她进来
Show her in.
欢迎来到东斯拉夫，亲爱的
Welcome to Eastern Slav, my dear.
我是斯维特拉娜贝利科娃总统
I am President Svetlana Belikova.
各位，请容我向你们 介绍我们的贵宾
Gentlemen, allow me to introduce you to our guest.
这位年轻女士是特别调查员
This young lady is a special investigator
来自于联合国 生化恐怖主义安全评估联盟
for the United Nations' Bio-terrorism Security Alliance.
日安，总统阁下
Good day, Madam President.
各位
Gentlemen.
生化恐怖主义安全评估联盟派我来这里
I have been sent here by the BSAA.
我的名字是艾达王
My name is Ada Wong.
喂，你
Hey, you.
"我不叫喂，你
My name is not, ""Hey, you."""
我是JD
I'm JD.
虽然这不是我的真名
Although that's not my real name.
那老头看起来不太妙
The old man's not looking too good.
他一直都是那张脸
He always looks like that.
希望你说的没错
Let's hope you're right.
总之，你到底来这个国家做什么？
Anyways, what are you really doing in this country?
换个问题问好吗？
Hey, a different question for a change.
我的意思是
Ugh. What I mean is,
在美国比在这里…
being in America is a lot more fun than
好玩多了，对吧？
being here, right?
我怎么会知道
I wouldn't know.
汉堡
The hamburgers, man.
炸鸡
The fried chicken.
你国家的食物太好吃了
Food in your country's fantastic.
叫我每天吃都行
I could eat it every day.
多谢你宝贵的意见
Thanks for the valuable insight.
还有好莱坞电影
And the Hollywood movies.
我超爱那玩意的
I love those things.
我有50张DVD
I have 50 DVDs.
没有一张是盗版
None of them are pirated.
我以为你们讨厌美国人
I thought you guys hated America.
我们当然讨厌
Sure, we hate it.
但是美国制产品？
But things made in America?
那可就是两回事
Now, that's different.
（来电）
不管你想怎么做
Whatever you do,
别按那个按钮
don't push that button.
我才不会上当
I'm not falling for that.
我不会允许他们追踪这通电话
No way I'll allow them to trace the call.
外面情况怎么样？
How are things out there?
看来城里旧区都被包围
Looks like they have the old pan of the city surrounded.
我们最好等着看情况如何
We'd better wait and see how things pan out.
生物有机化学武器
Bio Organic Weapons.
简称
Also known as
生化武器
B.O.W.s.
多数已开发国家与联合国
Most developed countries and the United Nations
反对使用并生产生化武器
are against the use and manufacture of B.O.W.s.
但是很不幸的
However, they are, unfortunately,
他们仍在世界各地的黑市交易流通
still traded on the world's black markets.
我迅速看了一下这份报告
From a quick glance at this report,
我想在激烈冲突中使用这些武器
I'd say that using these weapons in a real conflict
非常不切实际，对吧？
would be extremely impractical, no?
是敌是友
There's no way to differentiate
难以区分
between friend and foe.
没错，想彻底掌控
It is true that total control
多数生化武器
of most of the B.O.W.s
近乎不可能，直到现在
has been nearly impossible up until now.
最近研发出一项
But a new technology that changes that fact
改变这个现象的新技术
has recently been developed.
继续说
Tell me more.
近来先进技术
Recent technological advancements
可建立出人类
can establish a master/slave relationship
与生化武器之间的主仆关系
between a human and the B.O.W.s.
所以呢？
So?
他们怎么做，甩它鞭子？
What do they do, crack whips at it?
像训练野生动物那样？
Like they do with wild animals?
不尽然
Not exactly.
有机体，设计用来决定
Organisms, designed to determine
宿主为管理者还是受控者
whether a host is to be a controller or a controlee
占据宿主的身体
take up residence within the host's body
创造出介于人类与生化武器之间
and creates the perfect master/slave relationship
完美的主仆关系
between a human and the B.O.W.
与女王蜂与工蜂的关系
Similar to the relationship
很相似
a queen bee shares with her worker bees.
兄弟，能不能跟你谈一谈？
Yo, bro. Can I speak to you for a moment?
谈什么？
What about?
是关于酋长
It's about Ataman.
现在移动他可能有危险
It could be dangerous to move him now.
你的美国朋友对他也很有兴趣
And your American friend has also taken quite an interest in him.
不用
You don't...
不用担心我
You don't have to worry about me.
我们不能永远留在这里
We can't stay here forever.
谁在里面？开门
Who's in there? Open the door.
-有人吗？ -开门
-Anyone there? -Open the door.
打开
Open up!
不要抵抗
Stop resisting
-快点出来 -后退
-and come out. -Step back.
三，二
Three, two,
一
One!
不要动，手举高，不要动
Don't move. Hands in the air. Don't move.
-留在原地 -不要开枪
-Stay still. -Don't shoot.
把枪放下
Drop your guns!
我们走，带他们走
Let's go. Take them away.
离他…
Keep away
远一点
from him!
他变了
He's turned!
在楼下
Downstairs.
有人在地下室
Someone is in the basement.
开枪
Shoot. Shoot!
快跑
Quick, run!
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
酋长
Ataman.
动作快
We have to hurry.
他们．马上就要到了
They'll be here soon.
你
You...
走吧
go on ahead.
该死，本来一切都很顺利
Damn, just when things were going well.
我们可以赢得这场战争
We can win this war,
对吧？
can't we?
JD
时候到了
It's... It's time
我要走了
for me to go.
但我会在天堂
But I'll be rooting for you
支持你
from heaven.
起来，你这个笨蛋 你以为你穿的防弹衣是女生衬衫？
Get up, you idiot. You think that vest you're wearing is a girl's blouse?
我们得把酋长带离这里
We have to get Ataman away from here.
我早该猜到
I should have guessed.
美国制
Made in America.
等等
Wait.
那个美国人呢？
Where's the American?
大概死了吧
Dead, probably.
帮我一把
Give me a hand.
把我留下
Leave me here.
再继续这样下去
If we go on like this,
我们全都会死
we'll all be killed
更别提要发动什么
before we can launch an attack
首都攻击计划
on the capital.
走
Go.
创造一个新的未来
Create a new future.
这边
This way.
-我听见枪声 -他们来了
-I heard gunshots. -They're here.
我去看，马可
I'm going to go and check on Marco.
你去教堂找其他人
You head to the church and join the others.
好
Okay.
你真觉得我会上当？
Do you really think I'm gonna fall for that?
-杀了你 -我看起来像需要修剪吗？
-Kill you. -Do I look like I need a pruning?
别杀他
Don't kill him!
我不能同意这个要求
That's one request I can't grant.
钱考夫先生
Mr. Chenkov.
我告诉过你
I told you
别杀他
not to kill him.
-他是我的老师 -不是他死，就是我亡
-He was my teacher. -It was him or me.
别忘了
And don't forget,
他已经不再是你的老师
he wasn't your teacher anymore.
开枪
Shoot.
开枪，JD
Shoot, JD!
你该死的不开枪，带枪干什么？
Why the hell carry that gun around if you're not gonna use it?
不用担心
Don't worry.
下次我会开枪
I'll use it next time.
如果你决定开枪打那些东西 麻烦你瞄准头部，明白吗？
If you ever decide to shoot those things, shoot them in the head, got it?
等等
Wait.
往这走
This way.
两个大男人应该打得开
Two grown men should be able to open it.
这里是什么地方？
So, what is this place?
过去老游击队员
Old partisans used to hole up here
都躲在这里
back in the day.
他们真懂得怎么隔离敌人
They sure knew how to keep the enemy out.
这玩意不动如山
This thing ain't gonna budge.
退后
Stand back.
那边
That way.
这边
This way.
快点
Quick.
我就知道我不该…
Oh, I knew I should have
继续吃那些
stayed off the
垃圾食物
junk food.
快点
Hurry UP
-抓住他 -不要
-Get him. -No!
走开
Get away!
-抓住他 -离我远一点
-Get him. -Stay away from me!
抓住他
Get him.
不要
No.
-No.
-抓住他 -不要
-Get him. -No!
救我，救我
Please, somebody help me! Help me!
怎么回事？
What's happening?
走开，不要
Stay away! No!
走开
Get away!
救命
Help!
大家是怎么了？
What happened to everybody?
有躲藏的地方吗？
Anywhere we can hide?
有
Yeah.
你把所有人怎么了？
What did you do to everybody?
你们藏的寄生体跑了
The Plaga you were hiding got loose.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about!
你们宝贵的市民被寄生虫所控制
Your precious townsfolk are being controlled by a parasite.
会经由脊椎神经附着到中枢神经系统
It attaches itself to the central nervous system via the spinal cord.
你是说镇上的人都…
The people of the town are--?
他们永远不可能回复正常
They'll never be normal again.
-一定有办法的 -扯掉脊椎神经
-There must be something we can do. -Rip out the spinal cord,
但最好的结果只有瘫痪或死亡
but the best you could hope for is paralysis or death.
你骗人
You are lying!
如果你真是这样想 你为什么要杀掉那个老人？
If you really believe that, then why did you kill the old man?
但那是因为…
But that was--
因为你知道他永远不可能回复成人类
Because you knew he would never be human again.
他说的是真的
What he says is true.
我还有其他问题要问你
I have some more questions for you.
也许这一次，我们能够找到真相
Maybe this time we can get to the truth.
我们该怎么办？
What are we going to do?
-我得去拿 -去拿？
-I have to go and get it. -Go and get it?
为什么？
Why?
我们需要有人取代酋长的位置
We need somebody to take over for Ataman.
你也见到外面发生的事了
You've seen what's happening outside.
你想让这种事发生在你身上吗？
Do you want that to happen to you?
我们今日的所作所为 会是国家明日的希望
What we do today will carry the country into tomorrow.
就算如此
But even so...
我明天会跟其他人碰面
I'll meet up with the others tomorrow to plan
计划攻击总统府
an attack on the Presidential Palace.
做好万全准备
Get ready for that.
我，马上回来
I'll be back soon.
我要跟他说句话
I want a word with him.
-他去拿了 -拿寄生体？
-He's gone to get it. -The Plaga?
我不知道它叫什么名字
I don't know its name.
我只知道是长老给我们的
All I know is that it was given to us by the elders.
你们注射到身体里，好控制利卡？
You inject that stuff into your body to control the Lickers, right?
真有同情心的长老
Some compassionate elders you got there.
我们还能怎么办？
What other options do we have?
你知不知道整个世界都无视于我们？
Do you realize that the whole world ignores us?
我们就快要灭绝了？
That we are in danger of extermination?
省省吧
Save your breath.
在这件事上，我们的意见永远不会一致
We're not gonna see eye to eye on this.
帮帮我们
Help us.
我不想看到他变成怪物
I don't want to see him change into a monster.
艾琳娜会很难过的
Irina would not be happy about this.
艾琳娜
Irina?
我们从小就认识她
We knew her since we were kids.
巴迪的未婚妻
Buddy's fiance.
她是学校老师，信不信由你
She was a school teacher and, believe it or not,
巴迪也是
so was Buddy.
那些混蛋以为他们的学校
Bastards thought their school
是独立派的藏匿处，并且进行攻击
was a pro-independence hideout and attacked it.
艾琳娜跟孩子们死于攻击之中
Irina and the kids died in the attack.
所以他才来打这场仗
That's the reason why he's fighting this war.
在这之前，他从来没拿过枪
He had never even held a gun up until then.
我会假装你逃跑了
I'm going to pretend you escaped.
作为回报 你一定要抢在他之前拿到手
In return, you must get ahold of it before he does.
你现在相信我了？
So now you trust me?
我不知道你是谁，或是什么东西
I don't know who or what you are,
可我知道你救了我一命
but I do know that you saved my life.
你必须阻止沙夏
You must stop Sasha.
你可以在中央市场找到他
You'll find him in the central marketplace.
所有人注意，马上疏散
Everyone, evacuate immediately.
晚上八点正式展开任务
The operation begins at 2000 hours.
所有人注意，马上疏散
Everyone, evacuate immediately.
在找人？
Looking for someone?
艾达
Ada.
好久不见，里昂
It's been a long time, Leon.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
我正准备问你同样的问题
I was about to ask you the same thing.
是你释出寄生体？
Did you release the Plaga?
别逗我笑了
Don't make me laugh.
我对瑕疵品没兴趣
I'm not interested in defective products.
我是来帮他们一把
I'm just here to lend them a hand.
他们？
Them?
虽然他们看起来并不需要我帮助
Although it seems as if my help wasn't needed.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
如果他们攻击首都
If they attack the capital,
我的任务就轻松多了
it'll make my job a lot easier.
如此而已
That's all.
对了
By the way,
我们何时再继续…
when are we going to, um, carry on
那一晚未完之事？
from where we left off that night?
只要不是现在，随时候教
Any time but now.
你在生我的气，对吧？
You're angry with me, aren't you?
很符合你的个性
Suits you.
简短警告你一下
Quick word of warning.
这座城镇很快说要被肃清了
This town will be purged soon!
女人
Women.
将军？
General?
什么事？
Yes.
准备好后，随时可以展开攻击
You may start the attack when you are ready.
谢谢
Thank you.
带艾达王来见我 该给她看看这个
Bring Ada Wong to me. She should see this.
好极了，我得扮圣诞老人
Great. I get to play Santa Claus.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
没事，只是稍微降低了点戒心
Yeah, just let my guard down for a moment.
他们把我们横扫一空
They got us pretty good.
-巴迪呢？ -我到时他已经离开了
-Where's Buddy? -He already left by the time I got there.
-该死 -我们得赶紧离开
-Damn! -We have to leave now.
军方会将这整区
The military's gonna burn the whole area
跟里面所有东西烧毁
and everything in it.
-什么？ -没时间了
-What? -We're out of time
怎么了？
What's wrong?
没事
Nothing.
有件事我非做不可
There's just something I have to do.
你不需要了吗？
Won't you be needing that?
你是我兄弟
Ah, you my man. Heh, heh.
巴迪
Buddy.
太酷了，你还是人类
Cool. You're still human.
JD
你，你做了什么？
You. What have you done?
不，他不是我们的敌人，他…
No. He's not our enemy. He's--
我没事，走吧
I'm fine. Just go.
我不想惹麻烦
I don't want to cause any more trouble.
该是说再见的时候了
It's time to say goodbye.
JD!
等等
Wait.
我真的不在乎国家独不独立
You know, I didn't really care about independence.
我只是想跟你，还有我的朋友 过得愉快
All I wanted was to have fun with you and my friends.
还有…
And...
我原本很期待能带你参观美国
I was looking forward to showing you America.
相信我
Trust me,
这种事每次都会发生
I've seen this happen every time.
当你面对的是生化武器
When you're dealing with B.O.W.s,
是敌是友，毫无分别
there's no difference between friend or enemy.
它会夺走你的一切
It takes everything from you:
你战斗的目的，对他人的尊重
The cause you're fighting for, the respect you have for others.
我们必须阻止这种事再次发生
We have to keep this from ever happening again.
把寄生体给我
Give me the Plaga.
就我个人认为
As far as I am concerned,
这跟使用生化武器没什么两样
there is no difference between this and using B.O.W.s.
如果你想要阻止这种事继续发生
If you want to keep this from happening again,
把枪放下
put down your gun.
那好吧
Well, then.
这就是我的答案
That is my answer...
与你的答案
and your answer.
摧毁生化武器正依计划进行中
The eradication of the B.O.W.s is moving ahead according to plan.
绝不能让他们逃离这座城市 半个都不行
You mustn't allow even one of them to escape the city.
我们已做好万全准备与应变措施，阁下
We are prepared for all eventualities, madam.
还有一件关于艾达王的事
And one more thing, regarding Ada Wong.
有发现什么消息吗？
Did you find anything out?
生化恐怖主义安全评估联盟 没有名叫艾达王的员工
There is no one working for the BSAA by the name of Ada Wong.
你是说真的？
Are you serious?
是的，阁下
Yes, madam.
当然了
Of course.
中央大门
Central gate.
回报状态
Report your status.
中央大门回报
Central gate reporting.
－一切平静 -收到
-All is calm. -Roger.
睁大眼睛
Keep your eyes peeled.
三辆卡车接近中
Three trucks are approaching.
所有人注意
Heads up, everyone.
停车
Halt.
你昨晚去哪了？
Where did you go last night?
你不在饭店里
You were not in the hotel.
我去找老朋友
I went to meet an old friend.
这位老朋友
And this old friend...
他是间谍吗？
is he a spy?
你为谁工作，俄罗斯人？
Who are you working for? The Russians?
美国人？
The Americans?
这个就留给你想象了
I'll leave that to your imagination.
考虑到你永远无法离开这个国家
Considering that you will never be leaving this country again,
我想你最好站在我这一方
I would say it is in your best interests to stay on my good side.
真可笑
Very funny.
他们说你以前当过教练 原来是真的
So it's true what they said about you being a former instructor.
以前？我现在还是
Former? I still am an instructor.
什么事？
Yes?
恐怖份子闯过…中央大门了
The terrorists broke through the central gate.
如我先前所说 我们决定延后你离开的时间
As I said, we have decided to delay your departure.
无限期
Permanently.
令人佩服
Now, that's impressive.
我老是说
I keep saying
这些东西不适合当宠物
these things make bad pets.
我们遭到恐怖份子攻击
We are under attack by terrorists.
我们需要支援
We need reinforcements, now!
总统府快要守不住了
We can't defend the palace much longer. Aah!
抱歉，但我没时间留下来聊天
Sony, but I don't have time to stay and chat right now.
业余人士
Amateurs.
他们连搜身都没有
They didn't even give me a pat-down.
没想到这么轻易就能进来
I didn't expect to get into this place so easily.
做为一个旧核子庇护所
Pretty impressive for
这里算很厉害了
an old nuclear shelter.
想我吗？
So you missed me, huh?
对啊，你想得美咧
Yeah. In your dreams.
你也看到了吗？
You seeing what I'm seeing?
这里就像蜂巢
It's like a beehive.
你有查看这些里面吗？
Have you looked inside one of these?
是寄生体
It's the Plaga.
真令人惊讶
Big surprise.
过去培育的是工蜂
Workers have been cultivated in the past.
但这个…
But this...
这是第一次培育出
This is the first time that the dominant members
这个种类的上位成员
of the species have been cultured.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我在工作，别担心
I'm working. Don't worry about it.
我可担心了
Oh, I'm worried.
够了
Enough!
所以你是为了这个而来的
So this is what you're here for.
怎么样？
Well?
满意吗？
Are you satisfied?
满意，多谢你了
Yes, thank you very much.
他是谁？
Who is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
他是美国探员
He's an American agent.
这个疑问解决了
Well, now that we got that out of the way...
美国人？
An American?
你最好小心
You'd better watch out.
那老太婆 是会咬人的狗不会叫
That old broad's got a bite worse than her bark.
你说什么？
Say what?
在那里，在那里，开枪
Over there! Over there! Shoot!
停火，停火
Ceasefire! Ceasefire! Unh!
停火
Ceasefire!
别动
Don't move.
你到底知不知道
Do you have any idea
你的枪是指着谁？
who you are pointing your gun at?
我想想
Yeah, let me see.
你是养蜂人
You're the beekeeper.
养蜂人？
The beekeeper?
释出寄生体的人
The person who released the Plaga.
正如我所想的一样 你半点头绪都没有
Just as I thought, you haven't a clue.
我是这个国家的总统
I am the president of this country.
原来艾达是这个意思
So that's what Ada meant.
他是国家的敌人，杀了他
He is an enemy of the state. Kill him!
怪物冲破货物出口
Creatures broke through
他们往你们那里去了
the cargo entrance! They're heading your way!
开火
Open fire!
停火，停火
Cease fire. Cease fire.
救我
Help me!
撤退
Fall back! Aah!
你用了吗？
Did you use it?
杀了他
Get him.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我阻止不了他
I couldn't stop him.
你这个混蛋
You bastard! Aah!
救命！
Help!
杀了我，对你有什么好处？
What will you gain by killing me?
你有没有仔细想过？
Have you thought this through?
这个国家一旦独立，将由谁领导？
Who will lead the country once you gain independence?
你？
You?
我无意听取
I have no intention of taking advice
一个谋朝篡位的人的意见
from a pretender to the throne. Heh.
要是你想知道
In case you're interested,
所有长老，除了酋长
all of the elders, with the exception of Ataman,
都已经站到我这一方
have already come over to my side.
我向他们保证 将分原油利润给他们
They all said they would be happy to renege on independence
他们都说很乐意放弃独立
once I promised to share the oil profits with them.
不可能
That's not possible.
我原本也是这样以为
Yes, that's what I thought.
但很遗憾，是真的
But I'm afraid it's true.
闭嘴
Shut up! Unh!
我们在这里浪费时间的当下 世界各地出现变化
While we have been wasting time here, things have been happening in the world.
我们没时间
We don't have time to fight amongst ourselves
在这个小国里内斗
in this tiny little country.
闭嘴
Shut up!
真是好极了，一波未平一波又起
Oh, great. It just keeps getting better.
我们必需离开了
We have to go.
斯维特拉娜
Svetlana!
侦测到生化危机
A biohazard release has been detected.
疏散，疏散
Evacuate. Evacuate.
本基地即将焚毁
The incineration of the facility will begin shortly.
快跑
Run!
为什么会这样？
Why is it doing that?
（解除）
（完成）
你欠我一次
You owe me one.
为什么要帮我？
Why are you helping me?
别感激我
Don't get all sentimental on me.
我不是为了你
I'm not doing this for you.
因为没有其他人可以告诉世界真相
There's nobody else left to tell the world what really happened, that's why.
舱口
The hatch!
可以从这里上去
This will take us up.
该死
Damn it.
快一点
Hurry.
快点
Come on.
走吧
Let's get going.
这里是东斯拉夫共和国
This is an announcement
政府通告
from the government of the Eastern Slav Republic.
我们遭到
We are under attack
恐怖份子攻击
by terrorists.
可能使用了…
Biochemical weapons
生化武器
may have been used.
请立即疏散全城
You are ordered to evacuate the city immediately.
请远离首都五公里远
Please keep a distance of five kilometers from the capital.
打扰了
Excuse me.
什么事？
Yes, what is it?
军方已经撤离本城
Forces have been evacuated from the city
摆脱恐怖份子释出的生化武器
to escape the B.O.W.s released by the terrorists.
但是
However,
庇护所里的两人似乎逃脱了
it appears the two in the shelter have managed to escape.
为什么要浪费时间告诉我这件事？
Why are you wasting my time telling me this?
就让你知道的那个东西 除掉他们
Just let the you-know-what get rid of them.
我，马上去办
I'll see to it immediately.
救我
Help me!
做得好，老兄
Nice work, pal.
快离开那里
Get out of there!
你真不该这样做的
You really shouldn't have done that.
非要斗就是了？
You really want to fight this out, huh?
抱歉插一下手
Sony for butting in.
你跑得了一时，跑不了一世
You can run, but you can't hide.
来吧，别害羞
Ah, come on. Don't be shy.
现在！
NOW!
可能会有点痛
This might hurt a little.
我没想到
I didn't expect to be saved
会被生化武器所救
by B.O.W.s.
要去喝两杯吗？
Wanna go grab a few beers?
你请客？
Are you buying?
别管我，你走吧
You'll have to go without me.
他们找不到其他人玩吗？
Can't they find anybody else to play with?
不如你走吧，别管我
Why don't you go without me?
我喜欢有人陪
I like the company.
我们动作最好快一点
We'd better move a little faster.
今日，首都
Today the capital
遭到恐怖份子发起的猛烈攻击
was subjected to a powerful attack launched by terrorists.
他们以骇人听闻的大规模武器出击
They struck with fearsome weapons
也就是国际间
of mass destruction known as B. O.W.s,
所禁止的生化武器
which have been banned internationally.
我们国家别无所求
We as a country desire nothing more
只求和平生活
than to live in peace.
与反政府运动的长老们
Together with the elders of the anti-government movement,
仁慈地聆听我们的请求
who, might I add, graciously listened to our pleas,
设法避开我国史上
have managed to avert the most serious crisis
最重大的危机
in the history of our nation.
我相信这毫无疑问证明了 身为一个国家
I believe this is undeniable proof that as a country,
身为人民的我们
as a people,
有资格受到全面支持 进入国际社会
we are suitable for full acceptance into the international community.
身为领导人
As leader...
有问题吗？
Something wrong?
我不需要这个
I don't need this.
我就即兴演讲吧
I'll improvise.
长老们呢？
What about the elders?
结束了，所有人，就在不久之前
It's over. All of them. A little while ago.
我想我该在记者会上提到
I suppose I should mention that during the press conference,
恐怖份子将长老视为叛徒
that the terrorists executed the elders
处以死刑
as traitors.
是的，阁下
Yes, madam.
还有其他事吗？
Is there anything else?
我联络生化恐怖主义安全评估联盟 与国际刑警组织
I've already contacted the BSAA and Interpol
告知艾达王造成我们多大的损失
with regard to the damage we sustained because of Ada Wong.
国际间很快就会通缉她
An international warrant for her arrest will be issued soon.
几位恐怖份子成功脱离城市
A few of the terrorists managed to escape the city,
不过不用担心他们
but you don't have to worry about them.
另外两个人呢？
What about the other two?
只是时间上的问题
It's just a matter of time.
终于没人能够阻止我们
Finally, there is no one left to stop us.
是的，总统阁下
That's right, Madam President.
很好，马上召开记者会
Very well, let's start the press conference immediately.
是的，总统阁下
Yes, of course, Madam President.
终于
At last,
新的明天即将展开
a new tomorrow begins.
他们全程都在监看我
They were keeping an eye on me the whole time.
即将播出，五，四，三…
On air in five, four, three...
晚安，我是总统
Good evening. I am President--
总统阁下
Madam President.
我们遭到美国人与俄罗斯人攻击
We're under attack by the Americans and Russians.
什么？不可能
What? It can't be.
蹲下，狗东西
Stay down, you dogs.
不准动
Stay still.
快点，带走他们
Move. Keep them away.
快！快！
Move! Move!
-手举高！ -救我
-Hands in the air! -Help me.
所以
So...
美国人与俄罗斯人从一开始
The Americans and Russians had us in the palms of their hands
就紧紧掌握住我们的动态
from the beginning.
似乎是如此
That's what it looks like.
你先前知道吗？
Did you know about this?
不知道
No.
要是我知道，我就继续度假了
If I did, I'd still be enjoying my vacation.
喂
He?!
我失去了一切
I've lost everything.
我的导师
My mentor,
我的朋友
my friends.
我再也没有奋斗下去的理由
I have nothing left to fight for.
杀了我
Kill me.
求求你
Please.
我不想变成那些怪物
I don't want to change into one of those monsters.
那么…
Well...
我想我别无选择
I guess there is no other choice.
如果我是你，我也会有相同感受
I'd feel the same way if I was you.
但是自杀已经不在选项之中
But the option of taking our own lives no longer belongs to us.
一旦我们开始使用这个 就欠了那些死在我们身边的人
Once we start using these, we owe it to the people who died alongside us.
我们必需继续活下去
We have to continue living.
就算四肢瘫痪也在所不辞
Even if it means living the rest of our lives without the use of our limbs.
这就是我的回答
That is my answer
也是你的回答
and your answer...
巴迪
Buddy.
使东斯拉夫共和国支离破碎的内战
It's been three days since the end of the civil war
已经结束三天
that tore through the Eastern Slav Republic.
多亏美国与俄罗斯军队介入
The fierce battles
才得以中止激烈战役
were halted thanks to the intervention of American and Russian troops.
今天是第一天
Today marks the first day
世界各国媒体得以进入该城市
in which the world's media has access to the city.
由美国与俄罗斯领导的临时政府
A temporary government headed by the U. S. and Russia
将设立在东斯拉夫共和国 维持和平
will be set up in the Eastern Slav Republic to maintain peace.
斯维特拉娜贝利科娃辞去总统一职
Svetlana Belikova has resigned from her presidency
支持她的财团与前政府
and companies that supported her and the former government
将被驱离该国并且解散
will be thrown out of the country and dismantled.
上层从一开始说知情，对吧？
Top brass knew about it right from the beginning, didn't they?
稻草人的报告警告他们
The report from Scarecrow tipped them off
斯维特拉娜持有生化武器
that Svetlana was in possession of B.O.W.s.
所以他们才仓皇撤离
That's why they pulled out in a panic
仓促逃命，然后与俄罗斯人联手
and ran like hell to join forces with the Russians.
就为了保护自己，对吧
To protect themselves, right?
你错了
You're mistaken.
总统与此事无关
The president had nothing to do with this.
连我们都不知道怎么回事 你一定要相信我
Not even we knew what was going on. You have to believe me.
里昂
Leon.
-不… -我哪都不去
-I'm not going anywhere -Don't...
最终，什么都没改变
In the end, nothing's really changed.
一切皆按计划进行
Everything went according to plan.
基地已摧毁
The facility has been destroyed
我抢救出培育出来的寄生体
and I salvaged the cultivated Plaga.
但我还没决定
But I haven't decided
要不要把这东西寄给你
whether or not I should send it to you.
真的吗？
Really?
谢谢，你人真好
Thank you. That's very kind.
不过我还蛮想
Although, I sort of liked the idea
在个人资料上添上一笔 国际通缉犯的身份
of adding an international arrest warrant to my profile.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
-你会惹上麻烦的 -你有做吗？
-You're going to get in trouble. -Did you do yours?
-早 -嗨
-Morning. -Hi.
-早安 -早
-Good morning. -Morning.
快点走吧，我们要迟到了
Oh, come on, let's go, we're gonna be late.
早
Morning.